Be there and be square.
A Minecraft Movie is a family, fantasy, comedy film directed by Jared Hess.
Four misfits find themselves struggling with ordinary problems when they are suddenly pulled through a
mysterious portal into the Overworld: a bizarre, cubic wonderland that thrives on imagination.
To get back home, they'll have to master this world while embarking on a
magical quest with an unexpected, expert crafter, Steve.
Garrett, played by Jason Momoa.
Steve, played by Jack Black.
Henry, played by Sebastian Eugene Hansen.
Natalie, played by Emma Myers.
Dawn, played by Danielle Brooks.
Vice Principal Marlene, played by Jennifer Coolidge.
A Minecraft Movie is a 2025 fantasy adventure film based on the 2011 video
game Minecraft developed and published by Mojang Studios.
It was directed by Jared Hess from a screenplay Chris Bowman, Hubbel Palmer, Neil Widener, Gavin
James, and Chris Galletta, based on a story by Allison Schroeder, Bowman, and Palmer.
The film stars Jason Momoa, Jack Black, Emma Myers, Danielle
Brooks, Sebastian Hansen, and Jennifer Coolidge.
It follows four misfits from the fictional town of Chuglass, Idaho, that are pulled through a portal into a cubic
world, and must embark on a quest back to the real world with the help of a "crafter" named Steve.
Plans for a Minecraft film adaptation originated in 2014, when game creator Markus
Persson revealed that Mojang Studios was in talks with Warner Bros.
Pictures to develop the project.
Throughout its development, the film shifted between
several directors, producers, and story drafts.
By 2022, Legendary Entertainment became involved, and Hess was
hired as director with Momoa in talks to star.
Further casting took place from May 2023 to January 2024.
Principal photography began later that month in New
Zealand and concluded in April 2024.
Mark Mothersbaugh composed the score, and Sony Pictures Imageworks, Wētā
FX, and Digital Domain provided the film's visual effects.
A Minecraft Movie had its premiere at the Empire, Leicester Square in London on March
30, 2025, and was released in the United States and Sweden on April 4.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and was a box-office success, grossing $958 million against a budget of $150
million, becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2025 and the second-highest-grossing video game film of all time.
A sequel is scheduled for release on July 23, 2027.
The film explores themes of friendship, surrealism, exploration, portal, miner.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.